Preliminary Guide to the Pettaway Family Papers, 1944-1953 RL.01021
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Pettaway Family papers
1944-1953
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Pettaway family
RL.01021
1 Linear Feet
335 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Pettaway Family Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 1998.
Biographical Note
African American family from Waterbury, Conn. Grace and Winifred Pettaway are siblings; Grace attended Chaney State Teachers College. Winifred served in the military during the Korean War and attended North Carolina Central College in Durham (later North Carolina Central University).
Collection Overview
Collection contains letters to Grace and Winifred Pettaway from family members and their girl and boy friends during the years 1944-1953. They provide a glimpse of college and military life for African Americans during the 1940s and 1950s. The collection also includes photographs, event programs, greeting cards, newspaper clippings, certificates, and speeches.
African Americans -- Education; African Americans -- Education -- North Carolina -- Durham; United States. Army -- Military life -- History -- 20th century; African Americans -- Correspondence; Photographs; United States -- Armed Forces -- African Americans; African American college students; African American college students -- North Carolina -- Durham; Chaney State Teachers College; North Carolina Central University -- History -- 20th century; Pettaway, Grace; Pettaway, Winifred; Pettaway family; Pettaway family
- Accession #1998-0233
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
    - Grace Pettaway with Norris Rhinehart, 1944-1950, 4 folders (Box 1)
    - Grace Pettaway with Inez, 1944-1945 (Box 1)
    - Grace Pettaway with Winifred Pettaway, 1947-1948 (Box 1)
    - Grace Pettaway with "Mom", 1947 (Box 1)
    - Grace Pettaway with "Sis", 1947 (Box 1)
    - Grace Pettaway with Others, 1945-1948, 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Greeting cards and postcards, undated (Box 1)
    - James Pettaway with Elks and Masons (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (Box 2)
    - Winifred Pettaway - Military Papers (Box 2)
    - Winifred Pettaway with Others, 1948 (Box 2)
    - Winifred Pettaway with Others, 1952, 10 folders (Box 2)
  - Correspondence (Box 3)
    - Winifred Pettaway with Others, 1953, 7 folders (Box 3)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 3)
  - Speech, undated (Box 3)
  - Programs, Misc. (Box 3)
  - North Carolina Central College, Misc. (Programs, Clippings, Invitations) (Box 3)